<resources>
    <string name="app_name">30 days fitness</string>
    <string name="day_1">Day 1</string>
    <string name="day_1_exercise">Full-Body Warm-Up</string>
    <string name="day_1_description">Begin your fitness journey with a 10-minute dynamic warm-up, including arm circles, leg swings, jumping jacks, and light stretching. Warming up properly prepares your muscles for movement, increases blood circulation, enhances joint mobility, and reduces stiffness, helping to prevent injuries. This session is beginner-friendly, but it\'s important to perform controlled movements and avoid bouncing while stretching to prevent muscle strain.</string>
    <string name="day_2">Day 2</string>
    <string name="day_2_exercise">Bodyweight Basics</string>
    <string name="day_2_description">Master fundamental movements like squats, lunges, push-ups, and plank holds to develop strength and stability using your body weight. These exercises improve muscular endurance, enhance balance, and strengthen major muscle groups essential for daily activities. While suitable for beginners and intermediates, maintaining proper form—especially with squats and lunges—is crucial to protecting your knees and joints.</string>
    <string name="day_3">Day 3</string>
    <string name="day_3_exercise">Core Ignition</string>
    <string name="day_3_description">Activate your core with a focused workout featuring planks, crunches, leg raises, and Russian twists, designed to build abdominal strength and stability. A strong core improves posture, enhances athletic performance, and reduces back pain by supporting the spine. Although this workout is moderately challenging, it’s essential to keep your lower back pressed to the floor during ab exercises to avoid unnecessary strain.</string>
    <string name="day_4">Day 4</string>
    <string name="day_4_exercise">Cardio Blast</string>
    <string name="day_4_description">Boost your heart rate with a high-energy cardio session including jumping jacks, high knees, burpees, and fast feet drills. This workout enhances cardiovascular endurance, burns fat efficiently, and builds overall stamina. Due to its intensity, it is recommended for intermediate levels, and those with knee issues should modify high-impact movements or wear supportive footwear to protect their joints.</string>
    <string name="day_5">Day 5</string>
    <string name="day_5_exercise">Lower Body Focus</string>
    <string name="day_5_description">Strengthen your legs and glutes with squats, step-ups, calf raises, and glute bridges to build power and endurance. This session improves mobility, supports knee health, and enhances athletic performance. Proper form is key—keep your knees aligned with your toes during squats to prevent injuries. It’s suitable for beginners but can be adjusted in intensity for more advanced levels.</string>
    <string name="day_6">Day 6</string>
    <string name="day_6_exercise">Upper Body Power</string>
    <string name="day_6_description">Develop upper body strength with push-ups, dips, and shoulder presses to build endurance in your arms, shoulders, chest, and back. This session improves posture, increases muscle tone, and enhances overall functional strength. While moderately challenging, be mindful of shoulder alignment and avoid locking your elbows to prevent joint strain.</string>
    <string name="day_7">Day 7</string>
    <string name="day_7_exercise">Active Recovery and Stretching</string>
    <string name="day_7_description">Allow your muscles to recover with a gentle yoga-inspired stretching routine, including deep breathing and foam rolling. Stretching improves flexibility, relieves muscle tightness, and promotes relaxation, helping to prevent soreness. This beginner-friendly session is essential for injury prevention, but avoid overstretching or bouncing movements to keep muscles safe.</string>
    <string name="day_8">Day 8</string>
    <string name="day_8_exercise">High-Intensity Interval Training (HIIT)</string>
    <string name="day_8_description">Engage in an explosive HIIT session featuring short bursts of high-intensity movements like jump squats, mountain climbers, burpees, and sprint intervals. This workout maximizes calorie burn, boosts metabolism, and improves both aerobic and anaerobic endurance. While highly effective, HIIT is demanding, so beginners should start with lower-impact variations and allow sufficient rest between intervals to prevent overexertion.</string>
    <string name="day_9">Day 9</string>
    <string name="day_9_exercise">Core Strength and Stability</string>
    <string name="day_9_description">Refine your core strength with an advanced ab workout including hanging leg raises, bicycle crunches, and side planks. A strong core supports spinal health, enhances athletic performance, and improves balance. This session is moderately challenging, and it\'s essential to engage your core muscles properly while avoiding excessive strain on the neck or lower back.</string>
    <string name="day_10">Day 10</string>
    <string name="day_10_exercise">Lower Body Burnout</string>
    <string name="day_10_description">Power up your legs with Bulgarian split squats, deadlifts (if using weights), and explosive lunges to build strength and endurance. These movements enhance lower body power, support knee and hip stability, and contribute to overall athletic performance. This workout is more advanced, so maintaining good posture and engaging the correct muscles will help prevent injuries, especially in the knees.</string>
    <string name="day_11">Day 11</string>
    <string name="day_11_exercise">Upper Body Endurance</string>
    <string name="day_11_description">Develop muscular endurance in your arms, chest, and shoulders with an upper-body circuit including incline push-ups, triceps dips, and resistance band exercises. This session increases strength and improves posture, making daily tasks easier. While beginner-friendly, ensuring proper alignment and controlled movements is crucial to avoid shoulder or wrist strain.</string>
    <string name="day_12">Day 12</string>
    <string name="day_12_exercise">Speed and Agility Training</string>
    <string name="day_12_description">Improve coordination and athletic ability with agility ladder drills, lateral jumps, quick footwork drills, and shuttle runs. These exercises enhance reaction time, increase leg power, and improve overall fitness. While suitable for all fitness levels, those new to agility training should start slow and focus on controlled movements to avoid ankle sprains.</string>
    <string name="day_13">Day 13</string>
    <string name="day_13_exercise">Yoga for Flexibility and Mobility</string>
    <string name="day_13_description">Increase flexibility and relieve muscle tension with a yoga session focusing on deep stretches and mobility-enhancing poses. Yoga improves circulation, reduces stress, and enhances recovery, making it ideal for both active and rest days. This session is beginner-friendly, but listen to your body and avoid forcing stretches to prevent injuries.</string>
    <string name="day_14">Day 14</string>
    <string name="day_14_exercise">Full-Body Strength Training</string>
    <string name="day_14_description">Engage multiple muscle groups with compound exercises like deadlifts, push-ups, lunges, and rows. This workout promotes muscle growth, increases functional strength, and boosts overall endurance. It’s an intermediate-level session, so maintaining proper form—especially with weighted exercises—is essential for preventing strain or injury.</string>
    <string name="day_15">Day 15</string>
    <string name="day_15_exercise">Cardiovascular Endurance</string>
    <string name="day_15_description">Build heart health and stamina with a steady-state cardio session, such as jogging, cycling, swimming, or brisk walking. Cardiovascular training improves lung capacity, strengthens the heart, and helps with fat loss. This workout is suitable for all levels, but staying hydrated and pacing yourself is key to preventing exhaustion.</string>
    <string name="day_16">Day 16</string>
    <string name="day_16_exercise">Core and Lower Back Stability</string>
    <string name="day_16_description">Enhance core strength while protecting your lower back with exercises like bird dogs, dead bugs, and back extensions. A strong core prevents back pain, improves posture, and supports daily movements. This session is beginner-friendly but requires slow, controlled execution to avoid unnecessary strain on the spine.</string>
    <string name="day_17">Day 17</string>
    <string name="day_17_exercise">Plyometric Power</string>
    <string name="day_17_description">Boost explosive strength with plyometric exercises such as box jumps, broad jumps, and skater lunges. These fast, powerful movements improve speed, coordination, and muscle efficiency. While effective for building athletic performance, plyometrics are high-impact and should be done with proper footwear on a stable surface to reduce joint stress.</string>
    <string name="day_18">Day 18</string>
    <string name="day_18_exercise">Balance and Coordination Training</string>
    <string name="day_18_description">Enhance stability and control with single-leg exercises, stability ball workouts, and coordination drills. Balance training reduces injury risk, strengthens stabilizing muscles, and improves movement efficiency. This workout is suitable for all levels but requires focus and proper posture to maintain control and prevent falls.</string>
    <string name="day_19">Day 19</string>
    <string name="day_19_exercise">Functional Fitness and Mobility</string>
    <string name="day_19_description">Improve daily movement patterns with exercises that mimic real-life actions, such as kettlebell swings, squats-to-press, and suitcase carries. Functional training enhances strength, flexibility, and coordination, making daily tasks easier and reducing injury risks. This session is beginner-friendly but should be performed with proper posture to avoid muscle strain.</string>
    <string name="day_20">Day 20</string>
    <string name="day_20_exercise">Active Recovery Walk or Hike</string>
    <string name="day_20_description">Give your body a break while staying active by taking a long walk or enjoying a nature hike. Walking promotes cardiovascular health, boosts mood, and aids recovery by improving circulation. This is a low-impact, beginner-friendly activity, but wearing supportive shoes and maintaining good posture will help prevent foot or knee discomfort.</string>
    <string name="day_21">Day 21</string>
    <string name="day_21_exercise">Strength and Endurance Challenge</string>
    <string name="day_21_description">Combine resistance training with endurance exercises in a high-rep, full-body workout. This session builds muscle endurance, strengthens the heart, and improves overall stamina. Suitable for intermediate levels, it’s essential to listen to your body and rest if needed to prevent excessive fatigue.</string>
    <string name="day_22">Day 22</string>
    <string name="day_22_exercise">Lower Body Power and Explosiveness</string>
    <string name="day_22_description">Target glutes, quads, and hamstrings with weighted squats, step-ups, and kettlebell swings. This workout improves leg strength and explosive power for better athletic performance. It’s an advanced session, so using proper form and controlled movements is necessary to prevent injury.</string>
    <string name="day_23">Day 23</string>
    <string name="day_23_exercise">Upper Body Strength Challenge</string>
    <string name="day_23_description">Increase upper body power with advanced push-up variations, resistance band exercises, and overhead presses. Strong arms and shoulders improve daily function and athletic ability. This workout is moderately difficult, so proper alignment and controlled repetitions are key to preventing shoulder strain.</string>
    <string name="day_24">Day 24</string>
    <string name="day_24_exercise">Interval Sprint Training</string>
    <string name="day_24_description">Alternate between short bursts of sprinting and walking to improve speed, endurance, and fat-burning efficiency. Sprint training enhances cardiovascular health, boosts metabolism, and builds explosive power. This high-intensity workout is best for intermediate to advanced levels, and warming up properly before sprinting is crucial to avoid muscle strain.</string>
    <string name="day_25">Day 25</string>
    <string name="day_25_exercise">Core Endurance and Control</string>
    <string name="day_25_description">Engage your abs with advanced core exercises like hollow body holds, hanging leg raises, and Pallof presses. A strong core supports posture, enhances movement efficiency, and prevents back pain. This session is moderately challenging, and focusing on controlled breathing will maximize effectiveness while reducing neck strain.</string>
    <string name="day_26">Day 26</string>
    <string name="day_26_exercise">Flexibility and Recovery Yoga</string>
    <string name="day_26_description">Release muscle tension and improve flexibility with a deep-stretch yoga session. This workout promotes relaxation, prevents stiffness, and enhances mobility. It’s suitable for all fitness levels, but moving gently and breathing deeply will help avoid overstretching.</string>
    <string name="day_27">Day 27</string>
    <string name="day_27_exercise">Athletic Performance Training</string>
    <string name="day_27_description">Train like an athlete with agility drills, explosive jumps, and functional movements that improve speed and coordination. This session enhances overall athleticism and endurance. While effective, high-impact movements should be approached with caution, especially for beginners.</string>
    <string name="day_28">Day 28</string>
    <string name="day_28_exercise">Strength and Conditioning Circuit</string>
    <string name="day_28_description">Perform a full-body circuit combining strength exercises and cardio bursts for maximum calorie burn and muscle endurance. This workout boosts metabolism, improves muscular definition, and enhances overall fitness. It’s a challenging session, so pacing yourself and maintaining good form is key to avoiding fatigue.</string>
    <string name="day_29">Day 29</string>
    <string name="day_29_exercise">Mind-Body Connection and Mobility</string>
    <string name="day_29_description">Focus on mindful movement with mobility drills, deep breathing exercises, and body awareness techniques. This session enhances flexibility, reduces stress, and promotes recovery. Suitable for all levels, but attention to slow, controlled movements is crucial for maximum benefit.</string>
    <string name="day_30">Day 30</string>
    <string name="day_30_exercise">Fitness Test and Celebration</string>
    <string name="day_30_description">Assess your progress with a final fitness test, including timed push-ups, squats, plank holds, and a 1-mile run or walk. This session allows you to measure improvements in strength, endurance, and stamina. It’s important to track results without overexertion, as the goal is to celebrate progress rather than strain your body.</string>
</resources>